

ABOUT ME

Full-stack developer focused on API design and consumption. Ten years in architecture have honed my attention to detail and structured thinking.

Although my professional experience has been in teaching, I actively develop personal projects.

I would like to apply the solid foundations I've built in web development to a real product. I'm familiar with TDD, although I don't use it in all my projects, but I like it when an app looks clean and readable.

I really want to gain new knowledge and contribute what I have learned.

<u>Languages</u>

Spanish: Native English: Proficient Catalan: Intermediate French: Basic

TECH STACK

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, Next.js, PHP, Laravel, Java, Spring Boot, Python, MySql, PostgreSQL.

TOOLS

Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe
Photoshop, Trello, Visual Studio Code,
Git + Github, Bootstrap, Tailwindcss,
Sass, Styled Components, Jest, React
Testing Library, Vitest, PHPUnit, JUnit,
Axios, Json-server, Composer, Pupeteer,
SonicPi, Qgis, Docker, Website carbon
calculator, Digital beacon, Page speed,
Globemallow.

CONTACT ME

+34 675 49 79 44

alexandragalarzag@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/magalarza https://github.com/MAlexGG

MARIA ALEXANDRA GALARZA GALLARDO

Full Stack Developer | UX Designer | Architect

EDUCATION

User Experience Design (UX) professional certificate, (240-hour) | jul. - sep. 2022 Google - Coursera

Front-end web development, specialized in React.js (352-hour) | jan. - may. 2022 IT Academy - Barcelona Activa

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Styled Components, Javascript advanced and Typescript, errors and debugging, APIs, GIT and github. React, unit tests y test-driven development methodologies, Redux. Transversal skills module, where various soft skills are worked on.

Full Stack web development (850-hour) | apr. 2021 - sep. 2021

Factoría F5 - Barcelona School

Front-end development: UX/UI wireframe, mocking and prototyping interfaces, HTML5 and CSS3 advanced, atomic design, accessibility, Sass, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Javascript, Vue.js, Vuex, React.js, Axios.

Back-end development: OOP, Xampp, PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Postgresql, APIs, Katas, Node.js, Jest, PHPUnit, Firebase, Heroku, clean code, MVC, hexagonal architecture.

Best practices and agile metodologies: TDD, SOLID, DRY, KISS, Kanban, Scrum.

Version control system: GIT, Github, best practices in commits and branches.

Front End web development and agile metodologies (300-hour) | oct. - dec. 2020 Factoría F5 - Barcelona School

Agile Metodologies (Scrum and Kanban), interface development and user experience (UX/UI), HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, responsive design, mobile first, best practices, Github.

Master in Intervention and environmental management: people and society (75 ECTS) | 2017 - 2021 Universidad de Barcelona

Master in Sustainable intervention in the built environment (60 ECTS) | 2016- 2017 Universidad Politécnica de Cataluña

Architecture degree (6000-hour) | 2001- 2009 Universidad Católica del Ecuador

CERTIFICATIONS

- The Complete Spring Boot Development Bootcamp | 18h. Learn the Part Inc.
- The Complete Java Development Bootcamp | 31,5h. Learn the Part Inc.
- Introduction to Python | oct. nov. 2023, 50h. Eurecat
- Green Software for Practitioners | may. 2023, Linux Foundation
- Green Digital Skills | may. 2023, Inco Academy
- React.js essential | sep. 2021, LinkedIn Learning
- UI advanced | sep. 2021, LinkedIn Learning
- UX advanced | sep. 2021, LinkedIn Learning
- Vue.js essential | aug. 2021, LinkedIn Learning
- SEO SEM | oct. 2021, Cyberclick
- Conservation Project Planning | apr. 2020, National Geographic Society
- Introduction to Conservation | apr. 2020, National Geographic Society
- Aproximation to the wood construction | jun. 2019, Centre tecnològic forestal de Catalunya
- QGis Geographic information system | jun. 2015, Mapping GIS
- Project Management | mar. 2015, Cámara de la Industria de la construcción
- Human relations oriented to give good service to the user | jul. 2012, MRL-Ecuador
- Cadastre for executives | jun. 2010, Instituto Agustín Codazzi
- Artistic painting, charcoal, watercolor, pastel and oil | 2003 2008, Tito Heredia
- Digital Photography I jan. 2006, Todoarquitectura.com

VOLUNTEERS

- FemCoders Club | may. 2024
 - Participation in the presentation 'Green Software', Barcelona
- FemCoders Club in collaboration with Canòdrom | nov. 2023
- Participation in the live music and code event with the SonicPi tool, Barcelona
- Thoughtworks | oct. 2023
 - Participation in the podcast 'Gender equality in technology', Barcelona
- TopLap | sep. 2023
- Participation in the Jam Session with code 'from Scratch' with the SonicPi tool, Barcelona
- Factoría F5 | oct. 2021 actually
 - Collaboration for the pedagogic accompaniment for the promotions of front-end and fullstack in Barcelona
- Arquitectura sin fronteras España | oct. 2020
 - Collaboration in the round table topic: Human Scale in the city, Barcelona
- La Pedrera Foundation | oct. 2018 mar. 2019
- School Accompaniment Program for children from 6 to 12 years old, Badalona
- Un Techo para Ecuador | jul. 2006
- Roof construction program for indigenous communities, Riobamba

WORK EXPERIENCE

Factoría F5, Barcelona school | may. 2022 - present

Full stack web development Trainer | oct. 2022 - present

Design and support of the training process for bootcamps in full stack web development - FemCoders supported by Google.org, following agile methodologies and active pedagogy endorsed by Simplon, developing with good practices. Participation as a speaker in conferences and workshops.

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, PHP, Laravel, Java, Spring Boot, Scrum, Kanban, TDD, Tests, Katas.

Full stack web development Co-trainer | may. 2022 - oct. 2022

Support for the training process for full stack web development bootcamps, applying agile methodologies, clean code and best practices.

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React.js, PHP, Laravel, Scrum, Kanban, TDD, Unit Tests, Katas. Strengthen transversal skills aimed at job placement, additional training or entrepreneurship for groups in vulnerable situations.

Estela Julia website | nov. 2024

Diseñadora UX/UI y Desarrolladora web

Web design and development for Estela Julia singer with and admin dashboard.

PHI-Ecuador | sep. 2023

UX/UI designer and web developer

Web design and development for the Interuniversity Colloquium on Geomaterials and Architectural Heritage in Ecuador.

Tikibike | may. 2021

UX/UI designer

Website for a company that offers bike routes in France designed in Figma.

Enfiladissa Macramé | feb. 2021

Front-end web developer

Website catalogue of macrame products developed in HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Javascript vanilla, responsive.

Lego Arquitectura | jan. 2021

Wordpress web developer

Website for an architecture company developed with wordpress using elementor.

Área Metropolitana de Barcelona | apr. 2017 - jul. 2020

Architect

Collaboration with the IT department for the conceptual development of the geoportal of the department of Infrastructures. Maintenance of the GIS of transport actions. Updating of the document "Aproximació de les Infraestructures Metropolitanes". Drafting of the Manual of Styles for the Rondas de Barcelona. Generation of maps referring to traffic and tunnels. Collaboration in the drafting of urban landscape projects, 3d, photo montages, assistance in construction management and graphic design.

Novatam C.E.M. | mar 2015. - sep. 2016

Cadastral Project Manager and UX/UI designer

Conceptualización del Sistema Integral de Gestión Municipal "e-GAD" para la automatización de municipalidades del Ecuador, diseño de la imagen corporativa y diseñadora UX/UI.

Miski Chocolates | feb. 2012 - may 2016

Joomla web developer and content manager and co-founder

Website of a shop that sold personalized chocolates, developed in joomla (currently out of production).

Banco del Estado del Ecuador | aug. 2015

Technical trainer (20-hour)

Professional services to carry out the event called "Multi-purpose Cadastre, tool for Municipal development.

Estudio AO - Jaskran Kalirai Architect | aug. 2013 - sep. 2014

Architect

Architectural design Pichincha Bank Agencies, Páez - Gandara Residence, Corma Offices.

Empresa Pública Metropolitana de Servicios aeroportuarios, gestión de zona franca | jun. 2012 - jul. 2013

Supervision of the construction of the New Quito Airport contracted to the Luis Berger-Tahal company.

Dirección Metropolitana de Catastros | apr. - may. 2012

Supervision and quality control of the cadastral information survey carried out by Tecsult company.

Municipio Metropolitano de Quito, Administración Zonal Eugenio Espejo | apr. 2010 - jan. 2012

Appraisals and cadastres Team Leader

Direction and management of the decentralized department of appraisals and cadastres, a team made up of twelve people.

Patricio Endara Baca Architects | nov. 2008 - mar. 2010

Architect

Architectural design of different residential and service projects.